folger.edu 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy | Folger Shakespeare Library

The Folger takes your online privacy seriously. Our privacy policy is designed to let you and other Folger Website users know how we gather and use personal information we collect in connection with use of the Folger Website. 

We will take reasonable steps to protect user privacy consistent with the guidelines set forth in this policy and with applicable state and federal laws. We take these precautions in an effort to protect your information against security breaches.  However, this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by a breach of our security systems.  We are not responsible for the actions of hackers and other unauthorized third parties that breach our reasonable security procedures. By using the Folger Website, you acknowledge that you understand and agree to assume these risks.

#### Personal Information

You may visit the Folger Website anonymously without providing any personal information (such as your name, address, or email address). The Folger does not collect personal information from individuals unless they provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. If you ask to be added to a newsletter or other subscription list, purchase tickets, purchase items from the online store, donate to the Folger, register for free seminars and events, or use other online services at the Folger Website, we may ask you for personal information that may include your name, address, email address, phone number and credit card information including number, billing address, security code (CVV), and expiration date. 

#### How Personal Information Is Used

With the narrow exceptions provided below, the Folger uses your personal information solely for the purpose that you provided us the information.

We may partner with third party service providers to operate and manage our online ticket sales, online store and other online services.  Occasionally we share mailing addresses with third parties offering programs we think will be of interest to our audiences. In either event, your personal information may be shared with the third party service provider and will be used and protected in accordance with the policies of that company. 

In addition, we may be required to provide information to third parties, such as law enforcement authorities, to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; and to protect the rights, property or safety of the library, its users or others.  The Folger may also share your email address or other personal information with third parties for the purposes of protecting the Folger Website from fraud or from security risks, and to enforce compliance with the Folger’s privacy and other policies.

#### Opt-Out Procedures

You may always opt-out of receiving future emails and mailings. To stop receiving communications from the Folger, please email us at [webmaster@folger.edu](mailto:webmaster@folger.edu).

#### Cookies

The Folger may use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track your browsing activity on the Folger Website and the online services we work with in order to improve the user experience and manage the Folger Website. These technologies allow us, and entities that work with us, to increase the effectiveness of our promotional efforts and personalize our services and offerings to you. Unless you have initiated an online transaction that involves your disclosure of personal information, these tracking mechanisms and the entities that we work with do not have access to your personal information. Most web browsers accept cookies and other tracking mechanisms by default, but contain an option that may allow you to turn off this functionality if you prefer. If you turn off the cookies or other tracking mechanisms, some functions of the Folger Website may not be available to you.

#### Security and Your Credit Card Information

The Folger cares about the safety and security of your online transactions. We use a high-grade encryption key (RC4, 128 bit) and the https security protocol to communicate with your browser software. This method is the industry standard security protocol used by many financial institutions and e-commerce companies that makes it difficult for anyone to intercept the credit card information you send to us. Notwithstanding our commitments to protect your information from loss, misuse or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also risk that others could find a way to thwart our security systems.

#### Links

The Folger Website contains links to other websites. The Folger is not responsible for the privacy policies of or content on other websites, including any sites that may indicate a special relationship, endorsement by, or partnership with the Folger. The linked sites may collect personal information from you when you link to their site. Once you leave the Folger Website, our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service will not apply, and you access such sites at your own risk.

#### Notice to Children Under 13

The Folger and the Folger Website does not solicit or knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Visitors 12 years of age and under should remember that they are required to obtain an adult's permission before submitting any personal information to this or any other website.  If Folger learns that personal information of persons under 13 years of age has been collected without verifiable parental consent, then Folger will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.  To make such a request, please contact us at [webmaster@folger.edu](mailto:webmaster@folger.edu).

#### Notification of Changes

The Folger may modify or amend this policy from time to time. If we make any material changes, as determined by the Folger, in the way in which personal information is collected, used or transferred, we will post a modified version of this Privacy Policy on our website. We encourage you to periodically visit this page to review our most current Privacy Policy, and do likewise with our Terms of Use. Notwithstanding any modifications we may make, any personal information collected by Folger from you will be treated in accordance with the privacy policy in effect at the time information was collected, unless we obtain your consent otherwise.

#### Questions

Should you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [webmaster@folger.edu](mailto:webmaster@folger.edu).

___________________________

Last updated: 11/22/2017
